

4061 Green Drake Drive Wake Forest, NC 27587

919.345.1127 jay.clark@gmail.com

Summary

Information Technology professional with 20 years of industry experience in automation, cloud computing, systems administration, DevOps, agile software development, technical writing, and open-source software advocacy.

Skills

Cloud Computing

Amazon Web Services, Google Compute Engine, IBM Cloud, Microsoft Azure, OpenShift

Virtualization/Containerization

CloudFoundry, Docker, Istio, KVM, Kubernetes, Nutanix, Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization

Configuration Management

Ansible, Bash, Puppet, Chef, Salt, Capistrano, Terraform

Programming

Golang, Python, Swift (iOS), Ruby, Java, C#

CI/CD

CircleCI, Jenkins, Travis CI, Thoughtworks GoCD

Web Development

CherryPy, Flask, Django, Ruby on Rails, Laravel

Database

MySQL, PostgreSQL, mongoDB

Networking

Cisco Routing/Switching, DNS, OpenStack Networking (Neutron), TCP/IP

Storage

EBS (AWS), Ceph, NetApp, IBM XIV

Monitoring

Nagios, Splunk, Logstash, Kibana, Statsd, Collectd, Zabbix

Versioning

Git/Gerrit, Bazaar, Mercurial, Subversion

Cryptocurrency

Hyperledger, Ethereum

Professional Experience

IBM Corporation / Advisory Software Engineer

NOV 2016 - PRESENT, Research Triangle Park, NC

Hewlett-Packard Enterprise / Senior Software Engineer

AUG 2015 - JUNE 2016, Palo Alto, CA (REMOTE)

Cisco Systems / Cloud Services Engineer

JUL 2014 - AUG 2015, Research Triangle Park, NC

Red Hat Software / Platform Operations Engineer

AUG 2012 - JUL 2014, Raleigh, NC

IBM Corporation / Staff Software Engineer

JAN 2004 - AUG 2012, Research Triangle Park, NC

Education

Wake Technical / A.A.S. Computer Programming

Class of 2008, Raleigh, NC

Certifications

- Red Hat Certified Administrator in OpenStack #140-043-381
- Red Hat Certified Systems Administrator #140-043-381
- Cisco Certified Networking Professional, November 2001
- Cisco Certified Networking Associate, January 2001
- Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer, May 2000

Coursework

- Kubernetes Fundamentals, The Linux Foundation, November 2018
- Blockchain for Business An Introduction to Hyperledger Technologies, Linux Foundation/edX, July 2018
- The Data Scientist's Toolbox, John Hopkins University/Coursera, October 2017
- The Ultimate Python Programming Tutorial, Infinite Skills/Udemy, May 2014

Intellectual Property

- Use of Graphical Objects to Customize Content, Apr 3, 2007, #US11695785
- System, Method, and Apparatus for Graduated Difficulty of Human Response Tests, Feb 3, 2011, #US20110029781
- Mapping a Real-World Object in a Personal Virtual World, Apr 22, 2010, #US20100100851
- System and method for associating semantically parsed verbal communications with gestures, Dec 10, 2009, #US20090307595
- System and method for private conversation in a public space of a virtual world, Dec 10, 2009, #US20090303984

Publications

- Clark, Jason. "Convergence, Immutability, and Image-Based Deployments". Red Hat Developer Blog | Insights and news on Red Hat developer tools, platforms and more. 2014. Web.
 https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2014/01/22/convergence-immutability-and-image-based-deployments/>.
- Clark, Jason. "DSL Linux: Small distro that packs a big punch." IBM. 2006. Web.
 - http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-dsl.html.
- Clark, Jason. "Track bugs with Bugzilla on Linux." IBM. 2005. Web. http://ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-bugzilla.html.